<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Popular Science Video Archive on Academia Sinica Popular Science Video Archive</title>
    <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Popular Science Video Archive on Academia Sinica Popular Science Video Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://ASVideo.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2023/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2023/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Academia Sinica’s 112th Annual Science Popularization Award Ceremony invited Distinguished Researcher Ma Guofeng to share seismic monitoring technology, and introduced the research on using optical fiber to observe seismic waves, which can provide high-resolution seismic signals and analyze them in combination with big data. Taiwan has established a national seismic wave database to quickly obtain earthquake information. In the future, we will focus on more effectively feeding back earthquake information to the society, broadcasting the intensity of the earthquake to the location in real time, and actively developing communication-related work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2022/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2022/index.html</guid>
      <description>This video is to celebrate the 130th anniversary of the birth of Dean Zhu Jiahua. Distinguished Chair Professor Li Dingguo shares his deep friendship with Dean Zhu and his mental journey of physics research. The content of the lecture explores the properties of elements and emergent phenomena, such as superconductivity and collective phenomena of brain nerves. Academician Li pointed out that the Cooper pair is the key to the formation of superconductivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2021/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2021/index.html</guid>
      <description>This lecture invited Qiu Zhonglin, a researcher from the Institute of History, to give a lecture on the history of fine whaling in Chinese history. The research materials are scattered in history books, local chronicles and notes, and the time span is from the Han Dynasty to the present. However, China&amp;rsquo;s whale capture image data is relatively scarce, and traditional literati have limited understanding of the huge capture animals at sea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2019/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2019/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Mediterranean diet can help prevent frailty by including enough plant foods such as vegetables, fruits, nuts and oils, which help maintain health and reduce inflammation. However, the Mediterranean diet cannot be fully applied in Taiwan, and we need to make appropriate adjustments according to our own conditions. The balanced dietary recommendations of the US-Japan Dietary Guidelines For the elderly, ensuring that nutrients and protein intake meet the standards can help maintain overall physiological function and muscle mass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2018</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2018/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2018/index.html</guid>
      <description>This film mainly discusses the application of statistics in earthquake risk assessment, case-control study, EM algorithm and Kaplan-Meier curve, etc., and emphasizes its importance in public health, medicine, epidemiology and other fields. The video mentions how earthquake engineers use the EM algorithm to analyze surface acceleration for earthquake risk assessment and seismic design, and introduces the wide application of Kaplan-Meier curves in the biomedical field. At the same time, research by statisticians on reducing sampling error has also received attention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017</title>
      <link>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2017/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ASVideo.github.io/en/2017/index.html</guid>
      <description>The speaker of this event discusses the issues of privacy and privacy rights in the information society, and uses traditional architecture in Taiwan and the Florence Museum in Italy as examples to illustrate the understanding and changes in the concept of privacy in different social periods. The film compares the differences in the translation of privacy in different regions and delves into the spatial and legal aspects of privacy. The speaker emphasized that the modern concept of privacy is not only about protecting personal things and space, but also includes other meanings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>